Muhammad Hazim Bin Sulaiman

+6597221283 e0031232@u.nus.edu hajimss.github.io linkedin.com/in/muhammad-hazim-bin-sulaiman-3386191a0



Executive Summary

A Mechanical Engineering undergraduate, specializing in Offshore Oil & Gas Technology who is a keen learner. Having had read various Mechanical Engineering modules, in NUS, they have equipped me with apt knowledge and skillset to tackle engineering challenges, and especially in offshore, oil and gas industry.

Experience

Jul 2018 - Dec 2018

Mechanical Engineer (Intern), Schlumberger (Singapore Well Testing Centre - SWTC)

- Supported SWTC's new product development department in prototyping a new version of their multiphase flowmeter
- Created CAD (Computer-Aided Design) models, assemblies and drawings and assisted in physical assembles
- Extended support to other departments where help in calculation or modelling is needed
- Studied applications of Finite Element Analysis
- Obtained a clearer picture of oil and gas industry, including offshore technologies

May 2014 – Jun 2016

Firefighter (NS), Singapore Civil Defence Force

- · Performed firefighting and rescue operations as a firefighter
- Responsible for logistics and equipment maintenance of firefighting equipment within station

Education

Aug 2016 – May 2020

Bachelor of Engineering (Mechanical Engineering), National University of Singapore

- Specializing in Offshore Oil & Gas Technology
- GPA: 3.84 (after Year 4 Sem 1)
- Relevant coursework: Fluid Mechanics, Strength of Materials, Manufacturing Processes, Engineering Innovation and Modelling, Engineering Thermodynamics
- Technical electives: Offshore Oil and Gas Technology Specialisation Study, Robot Mechanics, Corrosion of Materials & Vibration Theory and Applications

Jul 2018 - Aug 2018

Summer Exchange, Hanyang University (Korea)

Jan 2012 - Dec 2013

A Levels, Meridian Junior College

Past Projects

Design Project (Autonomous Grass Cutter)

- Led a team of five to create an autonomous grass-cutting robot
- Collaborated with Catalyst Connector Pte Ltd and fulfilled their project objectives
- Allocated specific tasks to each member and monitored project's timeline by utilising project management tools
- In charge of robot's shell modelling and manufacturing, using Solidworks and machineries; structural analysis was also carried out with Ansys

Final Year Project (Supersonic Gas Ejector Design and Performance Evaluation)

- An individual project where pressure values of a supersonic gas ejector were investigated, and data and graphs were obtained to chart performances of gas ejectors
- Achieved a deeper understanding of thermodynamics and fluid mechanics

<u>Skills</u>

- Learnt C and C++ programming as an unrestricted module
- Proficient in CAD applications such as Solidworks, Solid Edge and Creo
- Experienced in FEA (structural analysis and computational fluid dynamics)
- Language: English (Native), Malay (Native), Spanish (Elementary)

Co-Curricular Participation

Mechanical Engineering Camp Committee

 Safety officer; supervised and kept a lookout for potential risks and its probability involved during camp activities and ensured hazards are kept at a minimum

NUS Open house

• Welfare; in charge of distributions of welfare gifts to open house guests

Temasek Hall (2016 - 2020)

- Main Committee of Sports Management Board;
- Participated in Floorball, Soccer and Touch Rugby for Inter-Hall Games 2017, 2018, 2019 & 2020
- Member of Vox (Chorale and Acapella group)

Temasek Hall (2020 - present)

• Class Ambassador; initiates gathering of alumnus for upcoming hall events